<p id="1">
<seg id="1">
<s id="1:1">While people in most parts of the world remain in their homes due to the COVID-19 pandemic, people who want to make the best out of this lockdown have become a course at Fêrgeha Kurdî.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="2">
<s id="1:2">​​Kurds and Armenians lived together in the village of Hacıkaş.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="3">
<s id="1:3">The village was burnt down three times by the Turkish state.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="4">
<s id="1:4">The Turkish state slaughtered a high number of Hacıkaş villagers in the 1930's, while many people were exiled in the massacre of Zilan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="5">
<s id="1:5">After the massacre, the village was completely vacated.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="6">
<s id="1:6">One of these buildings was the Haj Church, the historic Armenian Church.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="7">
<s id="1:7">At that time the name of the village was Kaş.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="8">
<s id="1:8">According to some villagers, this church was built on the site of a 3 thousand years old temple of the Urartu period.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="9">
<s id="1:9">The Kurdish Culture Week started with a march from Brouckere to Espagne squares.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="10">
<s id="1:10">The 6th edition of the Kurdish Culture Week has begun in Brussels.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="11">
<s id="1:11">The event area in Espagne square included replicas of historical buildings in Kurdistan, a stand where Kurdish culture and cousine can be tasted, a stage for concerts, book stands.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="12">
<s id="1:12">Your presence alone is a victory.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="13">
<s id="1:13">The very act of refusing oppression is a victory.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="14">
<s id="1:14">Fighting is a victory.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="15">
<s id="1:15">All they have killed is our fear.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="16">
<s id="1:16">With each sister who was captured, a warrior was born.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="17">
<s id="1:17">These poetic words continue, but they are not from any poem. These are from the Girls of the Sun film.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="18">
<s id="1:18">The Girls of the Sun film is about the Kurdish women’s fight against ISIS gangs.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="19">
<s id="1:19">“Girls of the Sun” is among the 21 films running for the Golden Palm in the 71st International Film Festival, and was screened on Saturday for curious audiences.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="20">
<s id="1:20">The film is about Kurdish women fighting ISIS, and is 115 minutes long.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="21">
<s id="1:21">Director Eva Husson reflects these concepts through an Êzidî woman, Bahar, who was captured by ISIS and achieved freedom later on.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="22">
<s id="1:22">Kurdish women’s victory</s>
</seg>
<seg id="23">
<s id="1:23">The film focuses on the ISIS attack against ISIS, the massacre, the capture of women and the victory of women who fought them.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="24">
<s id="1:24">WAR, DEATH AND PANIC</s>
</seg>
<seg id="25">
<s id="1:25">The main character in the film, Bahar.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="26">
<s id="1:26">It is played by exiled Iranian actress Golshifteh Farahani, who is known for her roles in Bahman Ghobadi films.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="27">
<s id="1:27">The film opens with French journalist Mathilde arriving in the Shengal mountains with a helicopter. The journalist is received by the fighter women.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="28">
<s id="1:28">The dialogue suggests that the journalist has been in Kobanê before, and knows some of the women from there.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="29">
<s id="1:29">We witness Mathilde and Bahar’s encounter as the film continues in an atmosphere of war, death and panic as Kurdish fighter women are trying to save the villages and towns from ISIS.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="30">
<s id="1:30">Pain, loss and a passion for freedom</s>
</seg>
<seg id="31">
<s id="1:31">Bahar has an image of the harsh, angry and disciplined fighter.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="32">
<s id="1:32">What they have in common is that they are both women, and mothers.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="33">
<s id="1:33">This brings them closer.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="34">
<s id="1:34">Bahar is a fighter woman who studied in France, and who lost her husband in the ISIS attack during her visit to her family in Shengal, was captured along with her son, was raped, but later managed to get her freedom.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="35">
<s id="1:35">Mathilde is a war correspondent journalist.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="36">
<s id="1:36">She lost her husband who had the same job in another war, and is worried for her child who is alone in France.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="37">
<s id="1:37">Their losses and searches are added to their womanhood and motherhood, and they have similar pains.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="38">
<s id="1:38">FIGHTING THE MALE MIND</s>
</seg>
<seg id="39">
<s id="1:39">The film Girls of the Sun doesn’t only analyze women’s fight against ISIS, it also stresses the fighting character of the women in Shengal.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="40">
<s id="1:40">It points out that some male fighter groups didn’t participate in the joint struggle in Shengal.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="41">
<s id="1:41">The women under Bahar’s command fight both ISIS, and this mentality.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="42">
<s id="1:42">The film brings to the light both the figting, resisting side of Kurdish women and their emotional, delicate and humane sides.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="43">
<s id="1:43">Songs in the Sorani dialect and dances reference the daily lives of Kurdish guerillas.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="44">
<s id="1:44">The film shows attempts to rescue the enslaved women and the conditions of women who were sold off, and gives credit to the positive role some imams played in the rescue.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="45">
<s id="1:45">GIRLS OF THE SUN IS A WOMEN’S FILM</s>
</seg>
<seg id="46">
<s id="1:46">The film ends with the Kurdish fighter women using tunnels to raid the headquarters of ISIS members.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="47">
<s id="1:47">While Mathilde is wounded in a Coalition bombing during clashes in the city.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="48">
<s id="1:48">Lead actresses Golshifteh Farahani and Emmanuelle Bercot are accompanied by Êzidî actress Zübeyde Bulut in the role of Lamia.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="49">
<s id="1:49">It looks like it will take home some awards from the festival.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="50">
<s id="1:50">Awazê Çiya music band composed of guerrillas has released a new song called “From mountains to seas”.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="51">
<s id="1:51">Among 200 countries, Iran is one of the few in which reading and learning in mother language is prohibited.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="52">
<s id="1:52">“Among 200 countries, Iran is one of the few in which reading and learning in mother language is prohibited,” the statement said.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="53">
<s id="1:53">It was also pointed out that “Imposing a system of formal reading and learning into a single language is an obvious act of killing languages that undermines the social status of other languages of the peoples of Iran.”</s>
</seg>
<seg id="54">
<s id="1:54">“Killing a mother tongue is the same as racism and ethnic cleansing.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="55">
<s id="1:55">A society that imposes only one language over other languages is a racist society.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="56">
<s id="1:56">There is no difference between imposing a race on other races or a language or a religion or an ideology.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="57">
<s id="1:57">They are all racism (Dr. Mohsen Renani, 2016).</s>
</seg>
<seg id="58">
<s id="1:58">Among 200 countries, Iran is one of the few in which reading and learning in mother language is prohibited.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="59">
<s id="1:59">It is clear that ignoring linguistic and national differences and imposing the language and literature of a nation is the service of the failed domination project.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="60">
<s id="1:60">This project only considers one language and does not recognize the language of millions of people in a large country like Iran.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="61">
<s id="1:61">Kurdish, Turkish, Arabic, Baluchi and Turkmen languages, like the native language of nations in Iran, represent the different culture and personality of these nations, as well as reflecting their thoughts, beliefs, and values transmitted from generation to another.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="62">
<s id="1:62">Therefore, the imposition of a system of teaching and reading in just one language is an obvious execution of languages, which undermines the social status of other languages in Iran.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="63">
<s id="1:63">Each year February 21 is a reminder of the mother language.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="64">
<s id="1:64">In 1999, the UNESCO announced in a clear step with an official offer from Bangladesh for February 21 to be titled as the International Mother Language Day.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="65">
<s id="1:65">The UNESCO also proposed a multi-lingual curriculum for countries that include several languages and different nations.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="66">
<s id="1:66">As the civil organizations in Marivan, we believe that recognition of different languages and the creation of multilingual education system in society would not be in conflict with preserving the country's sovereignty and maintaining a link between the Iranian peoples.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="67">
<s id="1:67">On the contrary, depriving people of their education and learning of their mother tongue and violation of individual rights leads to destruction and division.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="68">
<s id="1:68">As the civil society organizations in Marivan, the true representative of the culture and community of this land, we are keen to establish a multilingual curriculum in Iran; teaching and reading Kurdish in all schools in the Kurdish regions of Iran, from kindergartens to the final stages of studying.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="69">
<s id="1:69">We consider it essential and we do not want this linguistic extermination policy and violation of our cultural and social rights to be continued.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="70">
<s id="1:70">Marivan Literary Society</s>
</seg>
<seg id="71">
<s id="1:71">Vejîn Art and Cultural Association</s>
</seg>
<seg id="72">
<s id="1:72">Ronan Scientific and Cultural Center</s>
</seg>
<seg id="73">
<s id="1:73">Jiyanewe Popular Union for Combating Drugs</s>
</seg>
<seg id="74">
<s id="1:74">Green Chia Society</s>
</seg>
<seg id="75">
<s id="1:75">Rocyar Cultural Literary Community</s>
</seg>
<seg id="76">
<s id="1:76">Marivan Theatre Union</s>
</seg>
<seg id="77">
<s id="1:77">Religious Teachers Union in Hewraman</s>
</seg>
<seg id="78">
<s id="1:78">Marivan School Teachers Union</s>
</seg>
<seg id="79">
<s id="1:79">Jîn Health Club</s>
</seg>
<seg id="80">
<s id="1:80">The film Ji Bo Azadiyê (The end will be spectacular) about the resistance of Sur was screened at Mihemed Şêxo Culture and Art Center in Qamishlo.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="81">
<s id="1:81">Rojava Film Commune is organising special screening of the film ‘Ji Bo Azadiyê'.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="82">
<s id="1:82">Directed by Ersin Çelik, the film was shot in Kobanê.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="83">
<s id="1:83">150 publishers are participating in the fair with tens of thousands of books, but municipal officials have banned the promotion and sale of books in Kurdish.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="84">
<s id="1:84">A Kurdish language course has been started for children in the Russian city of Krasnodar.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="85">
<s id="1:85">Kurdish families have shown a great interest in this language course opened under the lead of the Kurdish Cultural Autonomy in Krasnodar.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="86">
<s id="1:86">Despite his old age, İşxan Ankosi says he has voluntarily joined the program in order to save the Kurdish children from assimilation and to help them serve their people in their own language.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="87">
<s id="1:87">Ankosi remarked that people had more interest in such activities in Russia before, adding; “Twenty years ago, when our people migrated here, we had serious concerns about the future of our language and culture.”</s>
</seg>
<seg id="88">
<s id="1:88">Speaking on the importance of mother language, Ankosi said: Societies continue their existence with their languages.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="89">
<s id="1:89">Even it might be late, we intend to do this work and promote similar activities.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="90">
<s id="1:90">We hope that our people will support us in the program.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="91">
<s id="1:91">Ankosi noted that along with the Kurdish language courses, the students will learn about the history of the Kurdish language and Kurdish culture.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="92">
<s id="1:92">Tilmanê Kaçax and Bekirê Kaçax are two Kurdish brothers who have voluntarily taken responsibility of the funding for the Kurdish course.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="93">
<s id="1:93">We read our first poem and voiced our first beautiful saying in Kurdish.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="94">
<s id="1:94">‘Need for support to the project.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="95">
<s id="1:95">Nûrê Aşîrî, one of the teachers in the course, said: In order to continue our cultural and linguistic activities, we will need the support of our people.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="96">
<s id="1:96">Without their support, it would be impossible to succeed in such efforts.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="97">
<s id="1:97">The YPG Press and Liaison Center issued a written statement about 7 fighters who fell martyrs in 2016.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="98">
<s id="1:98">The YPG statement said.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="99">
<s id="1:99">7 jihadists were killed, 19 others wounded and a vehicle was destroyed as a result of HRE operations.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="100">
<s id="1:100">Afrin Liberation Forces (HRE) announced the results of their latest operations against the occupation forces in northern Syria. Details of the HRE operations announced in a written statement are as follows;</s>
</seg>
<seg id="101">
<s id="1:101">On March 16, HRE fighters carried out a sabotage operation against Turkish-backed mercenaries at a checkpoint in Afrin, leaving 4 of them wounded.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="102">
<s id="1:102">On March 18, operations by HRE fighters in Afrin city centre killed 6 jihadists and wounded 15 others.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="103">
<s id="1:103">HRE fighters targeted the mercenaries in Celemê village of Jindires district, which left a mercenary dead and a vehicle destroyed.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="104">
<s id="1:104">7 jihadists were killed, 19 others wounded and a vehicle was destroyed as a result of HRE operations.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="105">
<s id="1:105">Three of these civilians, Mustefa Mihemed İbiş, Mihemed Xelil Şaban and Ehmed Arif İbiş, were kidnapped from the village of Badina, Rajo by the so-called ‘Firqat 112’ group.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="106">
<s id="1:106">Kamiran Sibhi Qasimo and Mihemed Ebdo, on the other hand, were kidnapped by the ‘Mehmet Fatih’ group from the village of Birimece, Mabata.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="107">
<s id="1:107">The statement reads as follows:</s>
</seg>
<seg id="108">
<s id="1:108">The invading Turkish state and its gangs bombed civilian settlements in Girê Spî last night.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="109">
<s id="1:109">The invading Turkish state and its gangs bombed the villages of Qizelî and Silîp as well as Qizelî wheat warehouse in the west of Girê Spî with artillery shots.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="110">
<s id="1:110">In the attack, a fire broke out affecting people's houses and agricultural lands.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="111">
<s id="1:111">The invading Turkish army is heavily bombing villages of Afrin and Til Temir.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="112">
<s id="1:112">The invading Turkish state and its mercenaries are bombing the village of Um El Kêf in Til Temir and the villages of Bênê and Aqibê in Shêrawa (Afrin).</s>
</seg>
<seg id="113">
<s id="1:113">Afrin Liberation Forces (HRE) announced that at least one jihadist was killed and another five wounded as result of their operations.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="114">
<s id="1:114">On April 2nd, HRE fighters hit the jihadists in Beradê village of Sherawa, leaving one mercenary dead and three others wounded.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="115">
<s id="1:115">On April 12th, HRE targeted the mercenaries in al-Bab city center, which left two jihadists wounded.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="116">
<s id="1:116">ID details of the three HRE fighters are as follows:</s>
</seg>
<seg id="117">
<s id="1:117">The Afrin Liberation Forces (HRE) reported that at least 6 invaders were killed and 5 injured in the actions they carried out against the invading Turkish forces and mercenaries in Shêrawa, Afrin and Azaz.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="118">
<s id="1:118">The Afrin Liberation Forces (HRE) stated that the actions took place between 15-18 April. According to the statement issued, two mercenaries were killed in Shêrawa, 1 in Azaz and 3 in Afrin.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="119">
<s id="1:119">The HRE's statement said:</s>
</seg>
<seg id="120">
<s id="1:120">On 15 April, our forces carried out a sabotage action against mercenaries affiliated to the invading Turkish army in the village of Kefer Nebo in Shêrawa. As a result of the action, 2 mercenaries died and 2 were injured.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="121">
<s id="1:121">18 April: Our forces carried out a sabotage action against the invading army mercenaries at the Wetani junction in the center of the city of Afrin. In this action, 3 mercenaries were killed and 3 injured.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="122">
<s id="1:122">Israel has carried out numerous attacks allegedly against Iran and Hezbollah, which have sided with Damascus since 2011, when the civil war began in Syria.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="123">
<s id="1:123">On April 20, according to regime sources, some targets in the Palmira desert were bombed by Israel.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="124">
<s id="1:124">The Syrian Human Rights Observatory reported that the posts of the Iranian militia were targeted in the attack, 3 Syrian fighters and 6 foreign fighters were killed.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="125">
<s id="1:125">Now they continued to be exposed to the attacks of the Turkish state as well as to the coronavirus pandemic threat.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="126">
<s id="1:126">The co-chair of the Sherewa Council, Evdo Berakat, said that they are trying to take measures to protect the people against the danger posed by the coronavirus infection.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="127">
<s id="1:127">We have neither hospital nor doctors.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="128">
<s id="1:128">If the coronavirus outbreak reaches us, the consequences will be devastating.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="129">
<s id="1:129">Someone should say stop to Erdogan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="130">
<s id="1:130">We are 14 families.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="131">
<s id="1:131">And, the Turkish state is attacking with mortars.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="132">
<s id="1:132">We no longer know what to do against these attacks.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="133">
<s id="1:133">Semar Ebdullah, co-chair of the Hesekê Canton Council, said that the Turkish state, which left one million people without water, has committed a crime against humanity by using basic needs as a weapon.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="134">
<s id="1:134">The curfew, which was announced on 23 March due to the coronavirus epidemic, continues in the northern and eastern Syria regions.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="135">
<s id="1:135">According to the Autonomous Administration sources, 80 percent of the local people do not leave their homes, following the curfew.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="136">
<s id="1:136">The measures taken in the region due to the virus are also being increased.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="137">
<s id="1:137">Ebdullah called on the people living in the regions of the Hesekê Canton (Şedade, Hall, Hesêkê, Til Temir, Amûdê, Dirbesiyê) to comply with the decisions taken by the Autonomous Administration.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="138">
<s id="1:138">Ebdullah accused the Turkish state and its mercenaries to have committed a crime against humanity by leaving the people without water.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="139">
<s id="1:139">Heyva Sor a Kurd has established a 120-bed capacity hospital in Hesekê to fight the coronavirus pandemic.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="140">
<s id="1:140">A 4.0 magnitude earthquake occurred in Kemaliye, Erzincan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="141">
<s id="1:141">Kandilli Observatory announced that a 4.0 magnitude earthquake occurred at 6.41 pm in Kemaliye, province of Erzincan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="142">
<s id="1:142">The Kurdish Revolutionary Youth Movement carried out two separate actions in Marseille to protest the Turkish occupation attacks.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="143">
<s id="1:143">A second action was held in the Marignane region.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="144">
<s id="1:144">Young people here hung a banner with the words "Defend Maxmur" on an overpass and drew attention to the attacks of the fascist Turkish state in South Kurdistan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="145">
<s id="1:145">Ömer Hayri Konar’s brother Ali Konar, Hamili Yıldırım's brother Polat Yıldırım and Veysi Aktaş' sister Melihe Çetin also applied to the prosecutor's office through their lawyers.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="146">
<s id="1:146">Young people in Stuttgart protested the isolation against Kurdish people's leader Abdullah Öcalan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="147">
<s id="1:147">The actions of Kurdish youth in Europe continue to protest the isolation imposed by the Turkish state against Kurdish people's leader Abdullah Öcalan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="148">
<s id="1:148">Young people shouted slogans like "Freedom for Öcalan", "Bê Serok Jiyan Nabe", "Revenge" and "Long Live Öcalan" in German, Kurdish and Turkish.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="149">
<s id="1:149">Upstream states in Mesopotamia must ensure the rights of people downstream to water.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="150">
<s id="1:150">Peoples’ Democratic Party (HDP)</s>
</seg>
<seg id="151">
<s id="1:151">Democratic Regions Party (DBP)</s>
</seg>
<seg id="152">
<s id="1:152">Socialist Party of the Oppressed (ESP)</s>
</seg>
<seg id="153">
<s id="1:153">Republican People’s Party (CHP)</s>
</seg>
<seg id="154">
<s id="1:154">‘78s Association</s>
</seg>
<seg id="155">
<s id="1:155">Peace Mothers</s>
</seg>
<seg id="156">
<s id="1:156">Dicle Amed Women Platform (DAKAP)</s>
</seg>
<seg id="157">
<s id="1:157">Code Name: Tekoşer Gever</s>
</seg>
<seg id="158">
<s id="1:158">Name Surname: Müslih İke</s>
</seg>
<seg id="159">
<s id="1:159">Place of Birth: Hakkari</s>
</seg>
<seg id="160">
<s id="1:160">Mother - Father Name: Mahbup - Ahmet</s>
</seg>
<seg id="161">
<s id="1:161">Date and Place of Martyrdom: 20 August 2019 / Medya Defense Areas</s>
</seg>
<seg id="162">
<s id="1:162">Comrade Tekoşer joined in the Kurdistan Freedom Struggle in 1993 at a young age and worked with active devotion on the war field for many years.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="163">
<s id="1:163">The Covid-19 pandemic has spread around the world.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="164">
<s id="1:164">There was no information available as to the damages after the earthquake.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="165">
<s id="1:165">According to the statement, the Turkish army launched an operation on April 15 in Xakurke region of Medya Defense Zones in southern Kurdistan, northern Iraq.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="166">
<s id="1:166">The Turkish jets shelled the vicinity of the Chemanke village in Gare region of Medya Defense Zones on April 14.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="167">
<s id="1:167">The air strikes did not cause any casualties in guerrilla ranks, but there was massive material damage to the civilian population's farmland.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="168">
<s id="1:168">On April 1, HRE carried out a sabotage operation against the vehicle of jihadist leader Abu Khalid in the village of Birç Heyder in Sherawa.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="169">
<s id="1:169">Khalid and two other jihadists were killed and the vehicle was completely destroyed.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="170">
<s id="1:170">SDF Commander General Mazloum Abdi calls in a video message for the measures against the spread of the coronavirus adopted by the autonomous administration in northeast Syria to be followed.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="171">
<s id="1:171">The village of Um al-Hosh in the northern Syrian canton of Shehba has been quarantined, reported the co-chair of the Health Committee of Northern and Eastern Syria, Dr. Ciwan Mustafa.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="172">
<s id="1:172">Internal Security Forces launched an operation.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="173">
<s id="1:173">According to the information received, two hand grenades were thrown at a civilian house by unidentified person(s) at around 1 am on Friday.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="174">
<s id="1:174">There was no loss of life in the attack.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="175">
<s id="1:175">At the same night, two vehicles belonging to the Syrian government forces were set on fire by an unidentified person or persons.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="176">
<s id="1:176">It is not known whether the two attacks are connected.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="177">
<s id="1:177">Internal Security Forces launched an operation following the attacks.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="178">
<s id="1:178">After ISIS cells had carried out a series of attacks in Raqqa recently, military forces increased security measures against the mercenaries in the region.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="179">
<s id="1:179">Two jihadists were killed and another three wounded in the sabotage action.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="180">
<s id="1:180">In the run-up to a visit by a Russian delegation to Ankara today, the Turkish-backed jihadists are said to have decided to withdraw from the M5 motorway between Idlib and Aleppo.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="181">
<s id="1:181">After the Syrian army took Saraqeb in the south of Idlib with Russian air and ground support, the militias supported by Turkey are said to have decided to withdraw from some areas along the M5 road.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="182">
<s id="1:182">The attacks killed a 65-year-old civilian named Elî Menle Ebû Şabo in the village of Aqiba in Afrin’s Sherawa district.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="183">
<s id="1:183">Afrin Liberation Forces (HRE) fighter Xalid Elo (Efrîn) was injured in resistance against the Turkish occupation on March 21 and died of his injuries on March 31.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="184">
<s id="1:184">Our comrade Efrîn was born in Afrin into a patriotic family.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="185">
<s id="1:185">Under the impression of the resistance against the occupation of Afrin by the Turkish army and its gangs, he joined our ranks.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="186">
<s id="1:186">He fought against the occupation with great anger and showed exemplary courage until his last breath.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="187">
<s id="1:187">Nom de Guerre: Efrîn</s>
</seg>
<seg id="188">
<s id="1:188">First and Last name: Xalid Elo</s>
</seg>
<seg id="189">
<s id="1:189">Mother’s Name: Meryem</s>
</seg>
<seg id="190">
<s id="1:190">Father’s Name: Elî</s>
</seg>
<seg id="191">
<s id="1:191">Place of Birth: Afrin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="192">
<s id="1:192">Place and Date of Martyrdom: Second stage of the Afrin resistance / 31 March 2020</s>
</seg>
<seg id="193">
<s id="1:193">Civaka Azad, which is working for Kurds in Germany, will organize an online panel on Thursday regarding the embargo imposed on Maxmur Refugee Camp for over 10 months.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="194">
<s id="1:194">Following the murder of MIT official Osman Köse in Hewlêr, South Kurdistan, on 17 July 2019, the KDP imposed an embargo on Maxmur Refugee Camp using this incident as a pretext.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="195">
<s id="1:195">In addition, camp officials from Maxmûr will participate in the panel live and provide information about the latest situation.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="196">
<s id="1:196">The meeting will begin at 7 pm on Thursday 7 May and can be followed at this address: https://civaka-azad.org/mexmur/</s>
</seg>
<seg id="197">
<s id="1:197">The body of Grup Yorum member Ibrahim Gökçek, who died two days after calling off the death fast he had carried on for 323 days, was brought to Kayseri for the funeral cemetery accompanied by the police at night.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="198">
<s id="1:198">On 5 April drug dealers were attacked in Amed Sur Melikahmet.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="199">
<s id="1:199">The house where drugs were sold was attacked and made unusable.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="200">
<s id="1:200">On 5 April, Turkish police officers patrolled in the Fiskaya neighborhood of Amed's Yenişehir district were attacked with handmade explosives, and the enemy was hit in the action.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="201">
<s id="1:201">On 12 and 15 April, 5 vehicles belonging to fascists were burned and destroyed in Kartal district of Istanbul.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="202">
<s id="1:202">On 19 April our self-defense revenge units protested against the attacks on Maxm and Zînî Wertê in Van İpekyolu Xaçort, blocking the streets. The invading enemy police officers who came to the area were shot at and withdrew .</s>
</seg>
<seg id="203">
<s id="1:203">Our units provided security in the neighborhood until morning.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="204">
<s id="1:204">On 23 April, in Arnavutköy, a bus belonging to AKP collaborator was burned and a commercial taxi was destroyed.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="205">
<s id="1:205">On 24 April three vehicles belonging to fascist collaborators were burned down in Esenler.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="206">
<s id="1:206">On 27 April, the vehicle of a fascist AKP council member was burned in Başakşehir.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="207">
<s id="1:207">The International Society for Human Rights (IGFM) has asked Turkish President Erdogan to release Kurdish politician Gülser Yildirim.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="208">
<s id="1:208">On May 2, the Turkish army launched a military operation on Mount Cudi in Şırnak countryside which covered the areas of Deriyê Xendekê, Deriyê Hirçê and Kasaphane.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="209">
<s id="1:209">The operation was ended without any results on May 5.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="210">
<s id="1:210">On May 5, guerrillas targeted a military post located between the areas of Dader and Siwaro in the region of Mount Cudi.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="211">
<s id="1:211">On the same day, the HPG carried out a sabotage operation near the village of Osyan in Besta region.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="212">
<s id="1:212">One billion women worldwide have been raped or harassed.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="213">
<s id="1:213">Women refuse to assume passively this violence.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="214">
<s id="1:214">The One Billion Rising campaign called on women to get on their feet and protest on February 14.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="215">
<s id="1:215">One in three women worldwide has been subjected to violence, beaten, forced to have sex, raped or mistreated. One in three women corresponds to 1 billion women.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="216">
<s id="1:216">This morning, Saturday, April 11th, the death sentence of Mustafa Salimi, a prisoner sentenced to death, was carried out in Saqez Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="217">
<s id="1:217">The prisoner escaped from the Saqez prison after the riots. According to Kurdish journalists and human rights activists, he was arrested in the Kurdistan Region after escaping from a prison and then handed over to the Iranian government.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="218">
<s id="1:218">Mustafa Salimi, was born on June 25th, 1967, was sentenced to 15 years in prison and death sentence by the Saqez Revolutionary Court, presided over by Judge Goodini, on April 5th, 2003 on charges of "membership in Kurdish parties, armed robbery, and moharebeh."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="219">
<s id="1:219">The prisoner's sentence was upheld by Branch 31 of the Supreme Court, and the prisoner went on a hunger strike several times during his imprisonment to protest the unfairness of his sentence.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="220">
<s id="1:220">On Tuesday, April 14th, a Kurdish citizen, Ismail Ardavani, 32, son of Jalal, from the village of Tarkhanabad, Marivan, was arrested by intelligence forces and transferred to the Sanandaj Intelligence Detention Center.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="221">
<s id="1:221">According to an informed source, the intelligence forces raided the personal home of the Kurdish citizen and detained him without providing any legal permission.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="222">
<s id="1:222">The informed source added: "Intelligence forces arrested this Kurdish citizen on charges of being a member of one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="223">
<s id="1:223">Ismail Ardavani is currently being interrogated at the Sanandaj Intelligence Detention Center.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="224">
<s id="1:224">The Second Branch of the Kermanshah Revolutionary Court has sentenced four Kurdish cultural activists, Shahriar Tahmasebi from Kermanshah, Ardeshir Mousavi from Kermanshah, Mustafa Bagheri Ashna from Kangavar, and Arsalan Hedayati from Qorveh, to 9 months prison each.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="225">
<s id="1:225">In an interview with Kurdpa, Shahriar Tahmasebi confirmed the news, saying that the Second Branch of the Kermanshah Revolutionary Court, presided over by Judge Shahrokh Moradi, had issued the verdict on charges of "propaganda against the regime and forming a group with the intent to disrupt public order."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="226">
<s id="1:226">Shahriyar Tahmasebi, Ardeshir Mousavi and Mostafa Bagheri Ashna were arrested by security forces on Thursday, July 5, 2018, and Arsalan Hedayati was arrested on Friday, July 5, 2018.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="227">
<s id="1:227">These four cultural activists were released on bail after interrogations.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="228">
<s id="1:228">Ardeshir Mousavi and Mostafa Bagheri Ashna had been on a hunger strike in Dieselabad Prison in Kermanshah during the detention period from Wednesday, August 8, 2018 to Wednesday, August 29, 2018 in protest of "deprivation of legal rights and deprivation of medical services."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="229">
<s id="1:229">A 14-year-old teenager, "Payam Rostami", died on Saturday, February 22nd, from a landmine explosion in Qasr-e Shirin.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="230">
<s id="1:230">On Sunday, April 19th, Kamran Abdipour, a former prisoner, was detained by plainclothes forces in Saqez and taken to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="231">
<s id="1:231">According to Abdipoor's family, plainclothes forces told them that Kamran had been arrested on charges of collaborating with fugitive prisoners at Saqez Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="232">
<s id="1:232">So far, the efforts of Abdipoor's family to find out the whereabouts of their child has been fruitless.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="233">
<s id="1:233">On Saturday, November 2nd, 2019, Kamran (Reza) Abdipoor was released from Saqez prison after 15 years in prison with the consent avengers of blood.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="234">
<s id="1:234">This Saqezi citizen was arrested during a clash that led to the murder of a man named "Mohammad Alizadeh" and was later sentenced to death.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="235">
<s id="1:235">Kurdpa Agency: Branch 2 of the Oshnavieh Criminal Court sentenced a Kurdish citizen to one year in discretionary imprisonment.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="236">
<s id="1:236">Branch 2 of the Oshnavieh Criminal Court has issued a sentence for this Kurdish citizen on charges of "cooperating with one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government".</s>
</seg>
<seg id="237">
<s id="1:237">On Thursday, July 11th, Ali Esmaili was arrested by the intelligence forces and on Saturday, September 7th, he was transferred from the Urmia Intelligence detention center to the Naqadeh Intelligence Bureau.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="238">
<s id="1:238">Also on Thursday, January 17th, 2019, this Kurdish citizen was arrested by the intelligence forces on charges of "cooperating with one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government".</s>
</seg>
<seg id="239">
<s id="1:239">Branch 101 of the Criminal Court II. Oshnavieh sentenced Rashid Naserzadeh, a Kurdish environmental activist to six years in discretionary imprisonment.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="240">
<s id="1:240">The court has charged this environmental activist with "gathering and colluding to commit crimes against national security and propaganda in favor of opposition and dissident groups."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="241">
<s id="1:241">The court, citing Articles 500 and 610 of the chapter on punishments and penalties deterrent by the Islamic Penal Code, and Article 134 of the Penal Code, sentenced this environmental activist to five years in prison on charges of "gathering and colluding to commit crimes against national security" and also, he has been sentenced to one year in prison on charges of "propaganda against the system", with the use of severe punishments, including previous prison terms.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="242">
<s id="1:242">The ruling was issued for the Kurdish activist, citing reports by the Oshnavieh Intelligence Bureau and the Judicial Bureau of the Oshnavieh Public Prosecutor's Office and Revolutionary Court.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="243">
<s id="1:243">This civil activist has been acquitted of "espionage for opposition groups" based on Article 37 of the Constitution and Article 4 of the Criminal Procedure Code.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="244">
<s id="1:244">This sentence was announced on Thursday, March 26th, to Rashid Naserzadeh.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="245">
<s id="1:245">This environmental activist from Oshnavieh was arrested by intelligence forces on Tuesday, December 3rd, 2019 was arrested on Piranshahr-Oshnavieh Road.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="246">
<s id="1:246">Rashid Nasarzadeh was released on 200 million Tomans bail, on Thursday, January 16th, 2020 after 44 days' detention.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="247">
<s id="1:247">On Tuesday, May 5th, a Kurdish citizen named "Idris Galedari" from Sanandaj was arrested by security forces and taken to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="248">
<s id="1:248">According to an informed source, six days after the arrest of the Kurdish citizen, his fate is unknown.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="249">
<s id="1:249">The informed source said: "This citizen of Sanandaj, while he had referred to one of the relevant companies for his personal car insurance, has been arrested by the security forces."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="250">
<s id="1:250">The informed source added: "After the arrest of this citizen, the security forces raided his private house and confiscated some of his personal belongings, including his computer."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="251">
<s id="1:251">The source said: " two brothers of Idris Galedari are members of one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="252">
<s id="1:252">No information is available on the reason for the arrest and detention of this citizen from Sanandaj, as of this writing.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="253">
<s id="1:253">On Saturday, April 25th, a Kurdish citizen named Jamil Khadem, 42, was detained by intelligence forces at the Sarv intersection in Urmia and taken to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="254">
<s id="1:254">Intelligence forces said the reason for the citizen's arrest was "cooperation with one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="255">
<s id="1:255">Until the moment of publication of this news, the citizen's family's efforts to find out whereabouts and his fate has been unsuccessful.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="256">
<s id="1:256">On Tuesday, May 20, an armed clash took place between Revolutionary Guards and an armed group in the Kaniguiz Heights between the villages of Rasha Deh and Dowaisa in Marivan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="257">
<s id="1:257">Hamzeh Camp Public Relations announced in a statement that the IRGC's Shahramfar Camp in an joint operation with the Kurdistan Intelligence Agency have clashed with an armed group in the Marivan public area.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="258">
<s id="1:258">The Hamza base claimed in a statement that two members of the militant group were killed and four others were wounded in the clashes.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="259">
<s id="1:259">Following the clashes, the Revolutionary Guards shelled the scene.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="260">
<s id="1:260">The Revolutionary Guards have attributed the clash to Kurdish opposition parties in the Iranian government, but so far no one claimed the responsibility for the clash.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="261">
<s id="1:261">On Tuesday, May 5, IRGC forces clashed with an armed group in Chehel Cheshmeh, Divandarreh, in which Shakiba Salimi, an IRGC commander, and Jafar Nezampour and Mohammad Shokri, two other IRGC members, were killed.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="262">
<s id="1:262">In recent days, a Kurdish citizen, Obaid Aziz Nejad, from Kermanshah, has been detained by intelligence forces and taken to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="263">
<s id="1:263">On Monday, April 6, a Kurdish kolbar named Borhan Jankanlu, 28, resident of Bazargan, Maku, was killed in a direct firings by government troops and two other Kolbars were wounded.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="264">
<s id="1:264">Borhan Jankanlu is married and has two children.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="265">
<s id="1:265">This morning, Sunday, May 3rd, a Kurdish Kolbar named "Mahmoud Moradi", the son of Haj Jalal, died as a result of direct fire from government troops on the "Hangeh zhal" border in Baneh.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="266">
<s id="1:266">This morning, Thursday, April 23rd, a prisoner accused of "murder" named "Sina Mohammadi" from the village of "Serenjianeh", Dehgolan was executed despite the efforts of civil activists to obtain the consent of the victim's family.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="267">
<s id="1:267">This prisoner was transferred to solitary confinement in Sanandaj Central Prison a few days ago to serve his sentence.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="268">
<s id="1:268">Sina Mohammadi had committed murder at the age of less than 18 and was later sentenced to retaliation.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="269">
<s id="1:269">In this regard, on Wednesday, April 22nd, the death sentence of a prisoner accused of "premeditated murder" named "Loghman Ahmadpour" from Baneh was carried out in Sanandaj Central Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="270">
<s id="1:270">This prisoner was arrested three years ago on charges of "premeditated murder" in Baneh and later sentenced to retaliation.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="271">
<s id="1:271">Also, on Tuesday, April 21st, Shayan Saeedpour, a prisoner sentenced to death, was executed in Saqez Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="272">
<s id="1:272">On August 19th, 2015, Shayan Saeedpour, while under the age of 18, in a clash with a citizen killed a person named Suleman Azadi.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="273">
<s id="1:273">He was sentenced to death by the First Branch of the Criminal Court of Sanandaj on October 23rd, 2018 under the chairmanship of Judge Vafaeian, and the verdict was upheld by the Supreme Court in February.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="274">
<s id="1:274">Kurdpa Agency: Students' Basij at the University of Ilam prevented the publication of a Kurdish cultural magazine.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="275">
<s id="1:275">According to a report by the Kurdistan Press Agency, students' Basij at the University of Ilam prevented the publication of the Persian literary and cultural magazine "Rebandan Khosha".</s>
</seg>
<seg id="276">
<s id="1:276">According to an informed source, blocking the publication of this cultural magazine at the University of Ilam was granted by the university's licensed publisher.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="277">
<s id="1:277">The students' Basij at the University of Ilam has been threatened by summoned Mohammad Ghiasvand, the holder of the literary and Persian cultural magazine "Rebandan khosha".</s>
</seg>
<seg id="278">
<s id="1:278">In its first issue, the literary and Persian cultural magazine "Rebandan khosha" addressed the poetry, culture, literature and history of Kurdistan, which prevented by students' Basij of Ilam University.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="279">
<s id="1:279">On Thursday, April 2nd, "Tahsin Dadras", a Kurdish political prisoner from the village of Sardoush, was transferred from Marivan to the central prison of Sanandaj.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="280">
<s id="1:280">According to an informed source, this Kurdish political prisoner has rejected the request of the Marivan Intelligence Bureau to cooperate with the agency and the deputy head of the Marivan Intelligence Department had pressured on this political prisoner.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="281">
<s id="1:281">This source added: For several times, Marivan Prison and Intelligence officials have opposed to leave of absence the political prisoner.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="282">
<s id="1:282">This political prisoner was transferred to Marivan Prison for a term of imprisonment in 1397 and was deprived of his leave during his imprisonment.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="283">
<s id="1:283">On Thursday, November 30th, 2017, Tahsin Dadras was arrested by the intelligence agents on charges of "cooperating with one of the Kurdish opposition parties" and transferred to the Sanandaj Intelligence Bureau after a week of detention.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="284">
<s id="1:284">This Kurdish citizen was sentenced to eleven years imprisonment in the district court in August 1397 on a charge of "acting against national security and cooperating with the Kurdish opposition parties" and then changed to a six-year sentence in the appeals court in Sanandaj.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="285">
<s id="1:285">This Kurdish political prisoner was denied "access to a lawyer" during his detention.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="286">
<s id="1:286">On Wednesday, May 13, a group of Kurdish Kolbars have ambushed by government troops near the two border villages of Madlu and Vakil in Chaldoran and they were injured severely.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="287">
<s id="1:287">Reza Sarshiri, Manaf Hassanzadeh were injured in the knee and Behzad Ramezani was injured in the back.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="288">
<s id="1:288">In this regard, On Tuesday, May 12, a Kurdish Kolbar named Kamran Molania, 32, son of Ismail, from the village of Guolan, was shot dead by Iranian government forces at the Sardasht's border.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="289">
<s id="1:289">Saeed Sangar, a political prisoner imprisoned in Urmia Prison, was sentenced by the Second Branch of the Revolutionary Court of this city to 15 years in prison, presided over by Judge Sheikhlou.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="290">
<s id="1:290">This morning, Tuesday, April 21st, Shayan Saeedpour, a prisoner sentenced to death, was executed in Saqez Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="291">
<s id="1:291">Yesterday, Saeedpour's family was called to the prison for the last visit, and the efforts of the citizens and trustees of Saqez to obtain the consent of the avengers of blood to prevent the execution of this prisoner sentenced to retaliation were fruitless.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="292">
<s id="1:292">On March 27th, Shayan Saeedpour escaped from Saqez Prison following an uprising in Saqez Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="293">
<s id="1:293">The prisoner sentenced to death was later arrested by intelligence and transferred to Sanandaj Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="294">
<s id="1:294">On August 19th, 2015, Shayan Saeedpour, while under the age of 18, in a clash with a citizen killed a person named Suleman Azadi.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="295">
<s id="1:295">He was sentenced to death by the First Branch of the Criminal Court of Sanandaj on October 23rd, 2018 under the chairmanship of Judge Vafaeian, and the verdict was upheld by the Supreme Court in February.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="296">
<s id="1:296">This morning, Saturday, April 11th, the death sentence of Mustafa Salimi, a prisoner sentenced to death, was carried out in Saqez Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="297">
<s id="1:297">The prisoner was transferred to solitary confinement in the past few days to serve his sentence.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="298">
<s id="1:298">The prisoner escaped from the Saqez prison after the riots. According to Kurdish journalists and human rights activists, he was arrested in the Kurdistan Region after escaping from a prison and then handed over to the Iranian government.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="299">
<s id="1:299">Mustafa Salimi, was born on June 25th, 1967, was sentenced to 15 years in prison and death sentence by the Saqez Revolutionary Court, presided over by Judge Goodini, on April 5th, 2003 on charges of "membership in Kurdish parties, armed robbery, and moharebeh."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="300">
<s id="1:300">The prisoner's sentence was upheld by Branch 31 of the Supreme Court, and the prisoner went on a hunger strike several times during his imprisonment to protest the unfairness of his sentence.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="301">
<s id="1:301">This morning, Saturday, April 11th, the death sentence of Mustafa Salimi, a prisoner sentenced to death, was carried out in Saqez Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="302">
<s id="1:302">Mustafa Salimi, was born on June 25th, 1967, was sentenced to 15 years in prison and death sentence by the Saqez Revolutionary Court, presided over by Judge Goodini, on April 5th, 2003 on charges of "membership in Kurdish parties, armed robbery, and moharebeh."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="303">
<s id="1:303">The prisoner's sentence was upheld by Branch 31 of the Supreme Court, and the prisoner went on a hunger strike several times during his imprisonment to protest the unfairness of his sentence.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="304">
<s id="1:304">Today, Saturday, May 16, a week has passed since the disappearance of Hedayat Hedayat Abdullahpour, a Kurdish political prisoner sentenced to death in Urmia Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="305">
<s id="1:305">So far, the political prisoner's family's efforts to find out his fate and whereabouts have been unsuccessful.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="306">
<s id="1:306">On Tuesday, May 12, Amnesty International issued a statement urging Iranian government officials to immediately determine the fate and whereabouts of Hossein Silavi, Ali Khosarji and Naser Khafajian (Khafaji), three prisoners on death row from the Ahwazi Arab minority, and Hedayat Abdullahpour, a prisoner from the Kurdish minority on the death row.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="307">
<s id="1:307">On Saturday, May 9, Hedayat Abdullahpour was taken out of the ward under the pretext of a phone card and then transferred to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="308">
<s id="1:308">Hedayat Abdullahpour was transferred to Urmia Central Prison after the interrogation on October 16, 2016.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="309">
<s id="1:309">On March 2016, this Kurdish political prisoner sentenced to death in the First Branch of the Revolutionary Court of Urmia on charges of " rebellion and membership in one of the Kurdish opposition parties in the Iranian government."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="310">
<s id="1:310">This verdict was violated in Branch 47 of the Supreme Court and his case was referred to the Second Branch of the Urmia Revolutionary Court for retrial.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="311">
<s id="1:311">The retrial of this political prisoner sentenced to death was held on December 26, 2017 in the presence of a representative of the Urmia Prosecutor, and he was sentenced to death for the second time.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="312">
<s id="1:312">Hedayat Abdullahpour's case was referred to Branch 47 of the Supreme Court after the ruling of the Second Branch of the Revolutionary Court of Urmia, and on Monday, October 8, 2018, the death sentence of this political prisoner was confirmed and his lawyer was notified.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="313">
<s id="1:313">The case of this political prisoner is currently in the Urmia Amnesty and Pardon Commission.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="314">
<s id="1:314">On Sunday, May 3rd, two Kurdish citizens from Sanandaj, Tariq Rahimpour and Benjamin Rahimpour, sons of Musa, were detained by intelligence forces and taken to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="315">
<s id="1:315">These two citizens were detained without any legal permission and their fate is unknown.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="316">
<s id="1:316">So far, the family's pursuits of these two citizens to find out about their fate have been fruitless, and the reason for their arrest has not been determined.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="317">
<s id="1:317">On Tuesday, May 12, a Kurdish Kolbar named Kamran Molania, 32, son of Ismail, from the village of Guolan, was shot dead by Iranian government forces at the Sardasht's border.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="318">
<s id="1:318">Iranian government forces fired directly at this Kolbar and a group of Kolbars without any prior warning.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="319">
<s id="1:319">Kamran Molania is married and has one child.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="320">
<s id="1:320">in this regard, on the evening of Friday, May 8, a group of Kurdish Kolbars were shot by Iranian government forces at the border of "Bolsur Sofla" in Khoy. One Kolbar "Loghman Chahargoosheh" was killed and two others named "Mansour Chahargoosheh and Meysam Mohammadi" were severely injured.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="321">
<s id="1:321">This morning, Tuesday, April 28th, a prisoner accused of "murder" named "Fayeq Sharifi" from Divandarreh was executed in Sanandaj Central Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="322">
<s id="1:322">This prisoner from the village of Tazehabad was arrested five years ago on charges of "premeditated murder" and sentenced to retribution (execution).</s>
</seg>
<seg id="323">
<s id="1:323">The Human Rights Organization of Iran has also announced that the death sentence of a prisoner accused of "murder" named "Yaser Rasouli" from Bokan has been carried out in Urmia Central Prison this morning.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="324">
<s id="1:324">This Bokani prisoner was arrested in 2011 on charges of "premeditated murder" and was being held in prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="325">
<s id="1:325">Mahabad Revolutionary Court sentenced a young Kurd man named Behnam Eliasy, son of Fatah to two years in prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="326">
<s id="1:326">The Mahabad Revolutionary Court has accused this young man of "supporting one of the Kurdish opposition parties in cyberspace".</s>
</seg>
<seg id="327">
<s id="1:327">This young Kurd was arrested on Friday, July 5, 2019, after being beaten by security forces without a legal permit.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="328">
<s id="1:328">Five Kurdish citizens named as "Sayed Ahmad Sabri", from Pasveh," Abdullah Hasanzadeh" from Pasveh, "Mohammad Ebrahimzadeh", from the Village of Khoranj, "Mohammad Eliasi" son of Mohammad Tahir, from Naqadeh, "Salam Bazargani", from Pasveh, have been transferred to the Urmia Sepah Detention center after being arrested.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="329">
<s id="1:329">These five Kurdish citizens were detained on Sunday, March 1st, by the intelligence agents without any legal permission.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="330">
<s id="1:330">Also, a Kurdish citizen named "Sayed Mustafa Sabri", a 70-year-old from Pasveh, was released after few hours of detention by the intelligence agents, and Abdullah Hassanzadeh was re-arrested by the intelligence forces after two days of detention and taken to the Revolutionary Guards Intelligence detention center and he has been relocated to Urmia Ettelaat Bureau.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="331">
<s id="1:331">Intelligence forces confiscated some of their personal belongings while detaining them.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="332">
<s id="1:332">No exact information is available on the charges against these five Kurdish citizens.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="333">
<s id="1:333">Photo: Mohammad Ebrahimzadeh, Sayed Ahmad Sabri, Salam Bazargani, Abdullah Hassanzadeh, Mohammad Eliasi</s>
</seg>
<seg id="334">
<s id="1:334">On Monday, March 30th, a Kurdish citizen named "Rahim Hassan Mahali", 50, son of Karim from Piranshahr, was transferred to ward three of Urmia Prison after serving two weeks in quarantine.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="335">
<s id="1:335">This morning, Tuesday, April 28th, a prisoner accused of "murder" named "Zourar Peyghami" from Oshnavieh was executed in Urmia Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="336">
<s id="1:336">This prisoner killed a citizen named "Kaveh Maroufi" three years ago in a personal dispute.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="337">
<s id="1:337">Attempts by Oshnavieh's clerics and civil activists to obtain the victim's consent to prevent the execution of the prisoner were unsuccessful, and the victim's family rejected the request for amnesty and pardon.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="338">
<s id="1:338">In this regard, on the morning of Monday, April 27th, a prisoner accused of "murder" named "Keyvanullah Moradi", 28, resident of the village of "Balbanabad", Dehgolan, was executed in Sanandaj Central Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="339">
<s id="1:339">In recent days, a young Kurdish man named Alan Bangin, 21, from the village of Kani Rash in Oshnavieh, was arrested by intelligence forces during his military service and taken to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="340">
<s id="1:340">Following the arrest of this young man, another young man from the village of Kani Rash, Yahya Ebrahimi, 21, was arrested by intelligence forces forces and taken to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="341">
<s id="1:341">Intelligence forces raided his family's home in the village of Kani Rash, and after searching his home, some of his personal belongings, including his computer, were confiscated and taken away.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="342">
<s id="1:342">No information is available on the reason for the arrest or whereabouts of the two Kurdish youths.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="343">
<s id="1:343">On Tuesday, March 17th, 2020, a Kurdish young man, Reza Osmani, from Marivan, was arrested by intelligence forces during Showarshama Sori ceremony.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="344">
<s id="1:344">Intelligence forces arrested this young man on charges of "raising the Kurdistan flag" and transferred him to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="345">
<s id="1:345">So far, the Kurdish citizen's family's follow-up for his fate has not yielded any results.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="346">
<s id="1:346">In this regard, on Tuesday, March 17th, a Kurdish citizen named "Mohammed Obeidi" from Marivan was arrested by intelligence agents due to raising the Kurdistan flag in Showarshama Sori ceremony.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="347">
<s id="1:347">The Sanandaj Revolutionary Court has sentenced Sirvan Ebrahimi, the head of Nojin Socio-cultural Association in Kamyaran's branch, to three years in prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="348">
<s id="1:348">The Sanandaj Revolutionary Court has charged this Kurdish teacher with "joining the opposition and acting against national security."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="349">
<s id="1:349">The head of the Nojin Socio-cultural Association in Kamyaran's branch was released on 500 million Toman bail on Thursday, September 12th.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="350">
<s id="1:350">This Kurdish activism was detained on Wednesday night, July 26th, without any legal permission by the intelligence agents.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="351">
<s id="1:351">On Tuesday, March 17th, a Kurdish Kolbar named "Sewan Sharifi", son of Khaled, from Baneh, died at the border of the city's "Hanga zhal" after government troops fired on him.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="352">
<s id="1:352">This Kurdish Kolbar has been targeted by government troops from close range without any warning.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="353">
<s id="1:353">The body of this Kurdish Kolbar was transferred to Baneh Forensic Medicine and has not yet been handed over to his family.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="354">
<s id="1:354">In this regard, in recent days, a Kurdish Kolbar, "Mohammad Qaderi", was severely injured in the Sardasht border crossing following by the direct firing of Revolutionary Guards.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="355">
<s id="1:355">On Friday, February 21st, a Kurdish citizen, Abdullah Sadeghi, was arrested by intelligence forces and taken to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="356">
<s id="1:356">This Kurdish young man was arrested without legal authorization and intelligence officials accused him about "propaganda against boycotting the elections".</s>
</seg>
<seg id="357">
<s id="1:357">So far, the citizen's family has been unsuccessful in finding out about his fate.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="358">
<s id="1:358">On Wednesday, May 20, a young Kurdish man named Shahab Aji, 23, son of Hussein from the village of Gargol in Naqadeh, was arrested after being summoned to the Urmia Intelligence Bureau.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="359">
<s id="1:359">This young Kurd was taken to a detention center for questioning, and his exact fate is unknown.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="360">
<s id="1:360">This young man has been constantly summoned to security agencies recently.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="361">
<s id="1:361">Until the moment of publication of this news, no information is available on the reason for the arrest of this Kurdish citizen.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="362">
<s id="1:362">On Thursday, May 21, Iranian government forces stationed at the Bitush base targeted a group of Kurdish Kolbars at the Sardasht border.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="363">
<s id="1:363">Following the firing of government troops, two Kurdish Kolbars, Mansour Ismaili, 30, from Baghi village, and Bakhtiar Qaderian, 32, from the village of Shalmash in Sardasht, were seriously injured.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="364">
<s id="1:364">due to the bullets, these two Kurdish Kolbars were severely wounded in the back.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="365">
<s id="1:365">These two Kolbars were taken to Sardasht Medical Center for medical treatment.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="366">
<s id="1:366">On Tuesday, March 17th, a Kurdish citizen, Mohammed Obaidi, from Marivan, was arrested by intelligence forces.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="367">
<s id="1:367">This Kurdish citizen was arrested during a ceremony of Showarshama Sori for raising the flag of Kurdistan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="368">
<s id="1:368">Intelligence forces transformed him to an unknown location after his arrest.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="369">
<s id="1:369">So far, the Kurdish citizen's family's pursuit about his fate has been fruitless.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="370">
<s id="1:370">On Thursday, March 12, a Kurdish youth named Khabat Mohammadi, from Sanandaj was arrested by plainclothes forces.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="371">
<s id="1:371">This young Kurd was taken to an unknown location after his arrest and his fate is not known.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="372">
<s id="1:372">Plainclothes officials have called the arrest of the young man "a member of one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government".</s>
</seg>
<seg id="373">
<s id="1:373">This environmental activist was arrested without any permission and was transferred to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="374">
<s id="1:374">The commentary titled ‘the United States Consulate in Erbil is the first source of destabilizing the Iran’s west borders’ reads: “At the time the likelihood of destabilizing the Iran’s west borders by the Washington administration is so high, the US government appointed an experienced expert (Steven Fagin) on the Kurdish question as the US consul in Erbil.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="375">
<s id="1:375">It is noticeable that during the Mustafa Hijri’s visit to Washington, Fagin was one of the US officials who met him’.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="376">
<s id="1:376">Mentioning the recent visit of the Democratic Party of Iranian Kurdistan’s leader to the United states, it reads: “Mustafa Hijri, the PDKI’s leader visited Washington and met some of the US Department of State’s officials, congressmen and think tank’s scholars from 11 to 17 June.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="377">
<s id="1:377">The commentary claims that the United States was behind the Iranian Kurdish opposition groups and reports that the Iranian government accused America of providing those groups with financial, military supports.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="378">
<s id="1:378">To discuss this topic, Kurdpa News Agency has briefly interviewed Karim Parwizi, a member of the PDKI’s Executive Board.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="379">
<s id="1:379">Karim Parwizi: The Iranian regime has always claim that the foreign countries are behind the Iranian people’s activities especially the Kurdish movement to achieve their primary rights.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="380">
<s id="1:380">Those claims aren’t something new since they have been repeated for forty years.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="381">
<s id="1:381">In early years, it claimed that the Kurdish movement was under the influence of Imperialism, Zionism and the Soviet Unions and other political blocks.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="382">
<s id="1:382">Whereas as we know most of them were against each other.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="383">
<s id="1:383">Kurdpa Agency: Does the United States support your activities?</s>
</seg>
<seg id="384">
<s id="1:384">Karim Parwizi: We have been asking the United States’ government, America’s nation, American’s NGOs as well as all the democratic countries and any force supporting liberal and social movements to help us in our fighting to bring about freedom.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="385">
<s id="1:385">Unfortunately, the US government hasn’t still come up to our expectation to support the Kurdish movement in the Iranian Kurdistan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="386">
<s id="1:386">We criticize the US in that it is expected to help other nations in their struggle to achieve freedom as well as stable peace.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="387">
<s id="1:387">We greatly appreciate receiving any support from the United States or any other country.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="388">
<s id="1:388">The Islamic Republic of Iran uses some terrorist groups like Hezbollah to suppress the Iranian people and plunder Iranian wealth to win the support of some countries like China and Russia in order to stay in power.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="389">
<s id="1:389">Therefore, the Iran’s suppressed nations have the right to find help and support for their struggle against this suppressing regime.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="390">
<s id="1:390">Kurdpa Agency: Iran claims that it is the US Consulate in Erbil that is planning the Rojhelat parties’ activities. Is it true?</s>
</seg>
<seg id="391">
<s id="1:391">Karim Parwizi: Even though we are looking forward to being politically supported by different sides whether it is the US Consulate, the US Department of State or any other side.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="392">
<s id="1:392">The Peshmerga activities and Peshmerga political-military tactics and strategies are planned by us not anybody else.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="393">
<s id="1:393">Following the PDKI’s intensive activities in Rojhelat, the IRGC’s top officials and officials from different state organizations in Iran threatened to destroy the party.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="394">
<s id="1:394">If the regime had succeeded in terrifying the Kurds in East Kurdistan, we couldn’t have seen the continuation of this nation’s movement and it might have surrendered after Khomeini issued Fatwa against this nation.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="395">
<s id="1:395">The Kurdish nation has been fighting the regime for four decades.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="396">
<s id="1:396">In recent days, a Kurdish citizen, Obaid Aziz Nejad, from Kermanshah, has been detained by intelligence forces and taken to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="397">
<s id="1:397">This Kermanshahi citizen was arrested without legal authorization and so far his family has been unsuccessful in finding out about his fate.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="398">
<s id="1:398">According to a source, intelligence forces have arrested this Kurdish citizen on charges of "cooperating with one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="399">
<s id="1:399">A few days ago, a Kurdish citizen from Kermanshah, Ismail Mansouri, was arrested by intelligence forces.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="400">
<s id="1:400">Intelligence forces have arrested this Kurdish citizen on the Dalahoo-Kermanshah Road without legal authorization.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="401">
<s id="1:401">No information is available on the fate and the reasons of this detention of this Kurdish citizen.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="402">
<s id="1:402">On Saturday evening, May 17, Turkish troops opened fire on a group of Kurdish Kolbars on the Qotur border in Khoy, one Kolbar, Bahram Yousefi, 35, from the village of Beljuk, was killed and another kolbar named Shemsaldin Omarpour was seriously injured.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="403">
<s id="1:403">These two Kolbars were shot by Turkish troops in the highlands of Qotur and taken to Van Turkish Hospital.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="404">
<s id="1:404">kolbar's body has not yet been returned to his family.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="405">
<s id="1:405">He is married and has four children.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="406">
<s id="1:406">Following the arrest of Kurdish citizens in Piranshahr on Tuesday, May 5th, five citizens, Ali Ghaderi, son of Rasoul, Mohammad Qaderi, son of Aziz, Hesam Aldin Pirani, son of Zahir, Amir Ghaderi, son of Khadar and Salam Kheri Aghlan, were arrested by security forces.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="407">
<s id="1:407">Also on Monday, May 4th, another citizen named "Vahed Qaderi", the son of Rasoul, was arrested by security forces.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="408">
<s id="1:408">These six citizens were taken to an unknown location after their arrest, and their fates are unknown.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="409">
<s id="1:409">So far, the exact reason for the arrest of these six citizens are unclear.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="410">
<s id="1:410">In this regard, on Monday, May 4th, two Kurdish citizens named "Ahad Mahmoud Hassan" and "Abu Bakr Mahmoud Hassan" from Piranshahr were arrested by security forces.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="411">
<s id="1:411">This morning, Wednesday, April 22nd, the death sentence of a prisoner accused of "premeditated murder" named "Loghman Ahmadpour" from Baneh was carried out in Sanandaj Central Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="412">
<s id="1:412">This prisoner was arrested three years ago on charges of "premeditated murder" in Baneh and later sentenced to Qisas.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="413">
<s id="1:413">Loghman Ahmadpour is 30 years old, married and has two children.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="414">
<s id="1:414">In this regard, on Tuesday, April 21st, Shayan Saeedpour, a prisoner sentenced to death, was executed in Saqez Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="415">
<s id="1:415">On August 19th, 2015, Shayan Saeedpour, while under the age of 18, in a clash with a citizen killed a person named Suleman Azadi.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="416">
<s id="1:416">The Urmia Military Court rejected the request for parole and probation of Farooq Sharoviriani and Amir Peyghami, two Kurdish political prisoners from the city of Oshnovieh in Kerman Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="417">
<s id="1:417">According to an informed source, these two Kurdish political prisoners went on leave a few days ago after the outbreak of the corona virus and applied to the Urmia Military Court for amnesty and parole.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="418">
<s id="1:418">The informed source added: Seyyed Ebrahim Hosseini, the judge in the case of these two political prisoners, and Shahram Panahian, the judge in charge of enforcing the verdicts of the Urmia Military Court, opposed the request of these two political prisoners and announced that they would not be paroled.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="419">
<s id="1:419">The informed source stated: Seyyed Ebrahim Hosseini has announced to these two political prisoners that it does not matter what decisions the judiciary and the leader of the Iranian government make, we are ordering here and we are against your request for probation and parole.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="420">
<s id="1:420">On Sunday, September 29th, 2019, these two political prisoners went on strike to protest the inappropriate behavior of the head of the Kerman Prison's security department and to put pressure on them.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="421">
<s id="1:421">These two Kurdish political prisoners were sentenced to a total of eight years in prison and deportation to Kerman Prison by the Urmia Military Court on Tuesday, December 5th, 2017.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="422">
<s id="1:422">Amir Peygami was sentenced to four years in discretionary imprisonment and Farooq Sharoviriani to four years in discretionary imprisonment, according to the verdict, which was announced on Saturday, December 16th, 2017 to the lawyers of these two Kurdish citizens.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="423">
<s id="1:423">A military court in Urmia has accused these two Kurdish citizens to "collaborating with Kurdish opposition parties of the Iran.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="424">
<s id="1:424">On Monday, January 22nd, 2018, Farooq Sharoviriani was deported from Urmia Prison to Kerman Prison, and Amir Peyghami was deported to Kerman Prison on Monday, July 16th, 2019.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="425">
<s id="1:425">On Tuesday, February 25th, intelligence forces arrested a Kurdish young man, Sirvan Mohammadi, from Urmia, and transferred him to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="426">
<s id="1:426">The arrest of this young Kurdish man was carried out without legal authorization, and his exact fate is not known.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="427">
<s id="1:427">According to an informed source, this young Kurd was arrested on charges of "membership in one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="428">
<s id="1:428">So far, the young Kurdish family's pursuit of his fate has been useless.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="429">
<s id="1:429">A few days ago, a Kurdish young man named "Pouya Parvaneh", a 18-year-old, son of Abdullah, was detained by the Revolutionary Guards near the border of Oshnavieh.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="430">
<s id="1:430">This Kurdish young man has been taken to a security detention center in Urmia for questioning.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="431">
<s id="1:431">No information is available on the reasons for arresting ofthe 18-year-old man until now.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="432">
<s id="1:432">Adil Bahrami, a Kurdish political refugee from Kamyaran, along with 32 other asylum seekers were deported from Turkey to Iran on Thursday December 26th.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="433">
<s id="1:433">Chia Sohrabi, a friend of Adel Bahrami, said in an interview with the Kurdpa Agency: on August 28th, Adel Bahrami introduced himself to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees in Ankara and the UNHCR settle him in the city of Amassiar as a refugee.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="434">
<s id="1:434">On December 14th, Adel Bahrami was detained by Turkish police at the Antalya airport when he left Turkey illegally and was transferred to Antalya prison on January 24th.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="435">
<s id="1:435">According to him, the trial of the Kurdish political asylum seeker was held in Turkish court by three lawyers in three stages and the court issued his deportation order.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="436">
<s id="1:436">This Kurdish asylum seeker stated: After the court ruling, Adel Bahrami was held in Gary Gandarmah in central Antalya for a year and transferred to Agri Camp and from Bazargan border deported to Iran on Thursday, December 26th.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="437">
<s id="1:437">Chia Sohrabi added: Prior to Adel Bahrami's deportation to Iran, he informed the UNHCR for the deportation of this political asylum seeker.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="438">
<s id="1:438">Sohrabi said at the end: "I handed over this Kurdish activist's documents to the Turkish police in a special file, but the reason for his deportation is unknown."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="439">
<s id="1:439">Chia Sohrabi, from Divandarreh, has filed for political asylum with the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees in Ankara two years ago and is awaiting an asylum application.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="440">
<s id="1:440">On Monday, February 24th, a Kurdish youth named "Rezgar Amini" from Urmia was arrested by intelligence forces.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="441">
<s id="1:441">The detainee was taken without legal authorization and transferred to the Urmia Intelligence Bureau for questioning.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="442">
<s id="1:442">Rezgar Amini was also detained in 2017 and he was temporarily released after interrogations.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="443">
<s id="1:443">Also on the same day, a Kurdish young man named Mohammad Faghizadeh from Piranshahr, was arrested by intelligence forces and his exact fate is unknown.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="444">
<s id="1:444">So far, the follow-up to the family of this citizen to find out about his fate has not yielded any results.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="445">
<s id="1:445">These two Kurdish youths have been arrested by intelligence forces on charges of "collaborating with one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government".</s>
</seg>
<seg id="446">
<s id="1:446">The Fourth Branch of the Sanandaj Court of Appeals, presided over by Judge Mostafa Tayari, upheld the sentence of Kamran Sakhtemangar, a Kurdish labor activist who had been sentenced to six years in prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="447">
<s id="1:447">The Sanandaj Court of Appeals rejected the appeal of this labor activist, citing paragraph A of Article 455 of the Code of Criminal Procedure, which upheld the appeal and ruled.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="448">
<s id="1:448">On November 19th, 2019, Kamran Sakhtemangar, a labor activist from Sanandaj, was sentenced to five years in prisonon charges of membership in one of the Kurdish opposition by the First Branch of the Revolutionary Court, presided over by Judge Hossein Saeedi, he was also sentenced to one year in prison, including previous days of detention and severe punishment on charges of propaganda against the regime.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="449">
<s id="1:449">This labor activist from Sanandaj was arrested on Thursday, September 5th, 2019, in connection with his activities in support of workers' rights in the private garden of Seyed Ali Hosseini, another labor activist in a village around Saqez, and he transferred to Sanandaj Ettelaat Detention Center.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="450">
<s id="1:450">This labor activist was released from Sanandaj Central Prison on Wednesday, November 27th, with a bail of 200 million Tomans.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="451">
<s id="1:451">On Monday evening, May 11, security forces arrested a Kurdish teenager named Sami Sharifian, 17, son of Hasan from the city of Pashweh in Piranshahr, and taken him to an unknown location.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="452">
<s id="1:452">According to an informed source, security forces raided the teenager's home and arrested him without any legal permission.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="453">
<s id="1:453">The first branch of the Sanandaj Revolutionary Court, headed by Judge Saeedi, has issued a three-year prison sentence for "Parisa Seifi", a Kamyaran cultural activist.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="454">
<s id="1:454">First Branch of the Sanandaj Revolutionary Court has charged thisl cultural activist with "propaganda against the system and membership in one of the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government."</s>
</seg>
<seg id="455">
<s id="1:455">This Kurdish cultural activist appealed against this verdict and her file has been referred to the Sanandaj Court of Appeal for reconsideration.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="456">
<s id="1:456">Parisa Seifi, a student of art and graphic, was arrested by intelligence forces at her residence in Sanandajon Tuesday, November 12, 2019.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="457">
<s id="1:457">This cultural activist was released on February 23rd, 2020, on a heavy bail.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="458">
<s id="1:458">On Monday, March 16th, a Kurdish citizen, Keyvan Azami, 37, from the village of Kohlineh, died in Sarpol Zahab due to the severity of the mortar blast caused by the eight-year war between Iran and Iraq.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="459">
<s id="1:459">In this incident, which took place on Sunday, March 15th, this Kurdish citizen was seriously injured and due to severe injury died in hospital.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="460">
<s id="1:460">More than three decades after the end of the eight-year war between Iran and Iraq, mine-affected areas and war munitions continue to be victimized in Kurdistan, and the Iranian government has so far failed to provide funding to clear mine-affected areas and war munitions in Kurdistan.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="461">
<s id="1:461">On the evening of Friday, May 8th, a group of Kurdish Kolbars were shot by Iranian government forces on the border of "Bolsur Sofla" in Khoy.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="462">
<s id="1:462">One Kolbar "Loghman Chahargoosheh" was killed and two others named "Mansour Chahargoosheh and Meysam Mohammadi" were severely injured.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="463">
<s id="1:463">On Tuesday, May 5th, Revolutionary Guards clashed with an armed group in Chehel Cheshmeh, Divandarreh.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="464">
<s id="1:464">The IRGC's Hamzeh base's public relations office said that Shakiba Salimi, one of the IRGC's commanders, along with Jafar Nezampour and Mohammad Shokri, two other IRGC members, were killed in the clashes.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="465">
<s id="1:465">Hamzeh Sepah's headquarters attributed the clash to the Kurdish opposition parties of the Iranian government, but so far no one has claimed responsibility for the clash.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="466">
<s id="1:466">On Sunday, March 1st, intelligence forces raided the home of Sayed Mustafa Sabri and his son, Sayed Ahmad Sabri, in the city of Pasveh, and arrested them without legal authorization.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="467">
<s id="1:467">Sayed Mustafa Sabri was released after several hours of detention, but his son remains in the custody of intelligence forces, the source added.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="468">
<s id="1:468">Sayed Ahmad Sabri was taken to an unknown location after his arrest and his fate is not known, the source said.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="469">
<s id="1:469">No exact information has been released as to the arrests of the two Kurdish citizens.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="470">
<s id="1:470">According to the statistics recorded in "Mine and Life", 37 citizens were killed and injured in a landmine explosion in Iran and Kurdistan during 1398.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="471">
<s id="1:471">Out of this total, 9 citizens lost their lives in a landmine accident in Khuzestan, Golestan, Urmia, Sanandaj and Kermanshah provinces.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="472">
<s id="1:472">In that statistic, 6 people were injured in a landmine explosion under the age of 18.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="473">
<s id="1:473">According to these statistics, most of the injured in the legs and arms have been mutilated.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="474">
<s id="1:474">Of the 42 landmine and munitions explosions in Iran and Kurdistan, 3 have resulted in the loss of livestock.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="475">
<s id="1:475">"Mine and Life" works to raise awareness about the dangers of landmines in mine-affected provinces and publishes reports and news about landmine explosions and ammunition.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="476">
<s id="1:476">On Monday, March 30th, a Kurdish citizen named "Rahim Hassan Mahali", 50, son of Karim from Piranshahr, was transferred to ward three of Urmia Prison after serving two weeks in quarantine.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="477">
<s id="1:477">This Kurdish citizen was detained by intelligence forces and after 32 days detention in Urmia Ettelaat Detention Center, they transferred him to the central prison of Urmia and then released on bail.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="478">
<s id="1:478">On the morning of Monday, April 27th, a prisoner accused of "murder" named Keyvanullah Moradi, 28, resident of the village of Belbanabad in Dehgolan, was executed in Sanandaj Central Prison.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="479">
<s id="1:479">This prisoner committed the murder of a citizen from Qorveh named Emad Khaledian five years ago in a clash.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="480">
<s id="1:480">This prisoner was transferred to Sanandaj Prison from Qorveh Prison some time ago.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="481">
<s id="1:481">Keyvanullah Moradi is married and has one child.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="482">
<s id="1:482">On Monday, April 6, a Kurdish kolbar named Borhan Jankanlu, 28, resident of Bazargan, Maku, was killed in a direct firings by government troops and two other Kolbars were wounded.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="483">
<s id="1:483">Iranian government forces have fired directly at them because government officials have thought they are carrying smuggle goods.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="484">
<s id="1:484">The injured Kolbars were taken to Maku Medical Center for medical treatment.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="485">
<s id="1:485">Borhan Jankanlu is married and has two children.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="486">
<s id="1:486">Learning Kurdish online with Fêrgeha Kurdî</s>
</seg>
<seg id="487">
<s id="1:487">Girls of the Sun against ISIS</s>
</seg>
<seg id="488">
<s id="1:488">New song by guerrilla band Awazê Çiya: From mountains to seas</s>
</seg>
<seg id="489">
<s id="1:489">Marivan's organizations on International Mother Language Day</s>
</seg>
<seg id="490">
<s id="1:490">Kurdish publications banned in Van Book Fair</s>
</seg>
<seg id="491">
<s id="1:491">Kurdish language course opened in Russia</s>
</seg>
<seg id="492">
<s id="1:492">YPG pays tribute to 7 fighters who fell martyrs in Manbij in 2016</s>
</seg>
<seg id="493">
<s id="1:493">Turkish-backed mercenaries kidnap 5 civilians in Afrin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="494">
<s id="1:494">Attack kills a member of security forces in Qamishlo</s>
</seg>
<seg id="495">
<s id="1:495">Turkish invaders attacks village of Xirbitbeqir in Girê Spî</s>
</seg>
<seg id="496">
<s id="1:496">HRE: Our main duty is the liberation of Afrin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="497">
<s id="1:497">Two more civilians abducted in occupied Afrin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="498">
<s id="1:498">Occupation forces attack villages in Ain Issa</s>
</seg>
<seg id="499">
<s id="1:499">MSD calls for liberation war for Afrin and Turkish-occupied lands</s>
</seg>
<seg id="500">
<s id="1:500">Newroz celebrated in Qamislo</s>
</seg>
<seg id="501">
<s id="1:501">Mercenaries clash among themselves in Afrin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="502">
<s id="1:502">Turkish invaders attack villages of Shêrawa and Shera</s>
</seg>
<seg id="503">
<s id="1:503">Turkish invaders bomb villages of Shehba</s>
</seg>
<seg id="504">
<s id="1:504">Turkish armed drone hits Kobanê public order forces</s>
</seg>
<seg id="505">
<s id="1:505">HRE: 8 invaders killed, 2 vehicles destroyed</s>
</seg>
<seg id="506">
<s id="1:506">HRE: Two mercenaries killed in Afrin and Azaz</s>
</seg>
<seg id="507">
<s id="1:507">Civilian from Gire Spi tortured to death by Turkish-backed gangs</s>
</seg>
<seg id="508">
<s id="1:508">Turkey and HTŞ meet after tension in Idlib</s>
</seg>
<seg id="509">
<s id="1:509">Turkish state bombing villages of Afrin and Til Temir</s>
</seg>
<seg id="510">
<s id="1:510">Israel carries out new air strikes against Syria</s>
</seg>
<seg id="511">
<s id="1:511">Shehba refugees face double threat: coronavirus and Ankara</s>
</seg>
<seg id="512">
<s id="1:512">Three people injured by fire in Newroz camp die in hospital</s>
</seg>
<seg id="513">
<s id="1:513">Turkey deploys 10,300 soldiers in Aleppo and Idlib since February</s>
</seg>
<seg id="514">
<s id="1:514">Curfew begins in North and East Syria</s>
</seg>
<seg id="515">
<s id="1:515">UNICEF worried for interruption of water supply in NE Syria</s>
</seg>
<seg id="516">
<s id="1:516">Turkish-backed mercenaries clash in Afrin and Serêkaniyê</s>
</seg>
<seg id="517">
<s id="1:517">Turkish army shells a village in Til Rifat</s>
</seg>
<seg id="518">
<s id="1:518">YPG: We have no connection with the Afrin attack</s>
</seg>
<seg id="519">
<s id="1:519">Turkey sets up new military points in Idlib countryside</s>
</seg>
<seg id="520">
<s id="1:520">Turkey has a fence erected around Bilbile district of Afrin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="521">
<s id="1:521">Heyva Sor a Kurd sets up Covid-19 hospital in Hesekê</s>
</seg>
<seg id="522">
<s id="1:522">4.0 magnitude earthquake in Erzincan</s>
</seg>
<seg id="523">
<s id="1:523">Young Kurdish activists stage demonstrations in Marseille</s>
</seg>
<seg id="524">
<s id="1:524">Families and lawyers apply to visit Imralı</s>
</seg>
<seg id="525">
<s id="1:525">UN calls on governments to reduce the number of prisoners</s>
</seg>
<seg id="526">
<s id="1:526">Danish parties condemn attack on Maxmur Camp</s>
</seg>
<seg id="527">
<s id="1:527">Officials say 59 people died of coronavirus in the past 24 hours</s>
</seg>
<seg id="528">
<s id="1:528">Activists in Bern and Stuttgart protest Turkey</s>
</seg>
<seg id="529">
<s id="1:529">HDP calls for the release of prisoners over coronavirus threat</s>
</seg>
<seg id="530">
<s id="1:530">Young people march for Öcalan in Paris</s>
</seg>
<seg id="531">
<s id="1:531">Democratic Forces Union condemns attack against Maxmur</s>
</seg>
<seg id="532">
<s id="1:532">Ecology Platform: Forests are burned for "security reasons"</s>
</seg>
<seg id="533">
<s id="1:533">Turkish warplanes bomb the region of Bradost</s>
</seg>
<seg id="534">
<s id="1:534">Curfew in Southern Kurdistan extended until May</s>
</seg>
<seg id="535">
<s id="1:535">Long March to Zînî Wertê faces obstacles</s>
</seg>
<seg id="536">
<s id="1:536">Turkish armed drones bomb Maxmur - UPDATED</s>
</seg>
<seg id="537">
<s id="1:537">Turkish state makes new military shipments to South Kurdistan</s>
</seg>
<seg id="538">
<s id="1:538">Warplanes bomb Mount Qereçox in Maxmur</s>
</seg>
<seg id="539">
<s id="1:539">HPG pays tribute to commander Tekoşer Gever</s>
</seg>
<seg id="540">
<s id="1:540">Reconnaissance flights over Maxmur continue</s>
</seg>
<seg id="541">
<s id="1:541">KCK: This Ramadan should bring unity and freedom to Kurds</s>
</seg>
<seg id="542">
<s id="1:542">KCK calls for strengthened solidarity and organization</s>
</seg>
<seg id="543">
<s id="1:543">HPG: Three Turkish soldiers killed in Xakurke</s>
</seg>
<seg id="544">
<s id="1:544">8 March celebrations in Gothenburg and Örebro</s>
</seg>
<seg id="545">
<s id="1:545">Another civilian kidnapped in occupied Afrin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="546">
<s id="1:546">Autonomous administration condemns Turkish attack on Kobanê</s>
</seg>
<seg id="547">
<s id="1:547">Attack on a checkpoint causes material damage in Qamishlo</s>
</seg>
<seg id="548">
<s id="1:548">Village in Shehba under quarantine over corona suspicion</s>
</seg>
<seg id="549">
<s id="1:549">Child killed in mine explosion in Ain Issa</s>
</seg>
<seg id="550">
<s id="1:550">Aleppo under full control of the Syrian regime</s>
</seg>
<seg id="551">
<s id="1:551">Turkish-backed militias set to withdraw from M5</s>
</seg>
<seg id="552">
<s id="1:552">Fierce attacks kill a 65-year-old in a village of Afrin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="553">
<s id="1:553">Turkish-backed militias set to withdraw from M5</s>
</seg>
<seg id="554">
<s id="1:554">Car bomb explodes in Serêkaniyê</s>
</seg>
<seg id="555">
<s id="1:555">Clash between Turkish-backed mercenaries in Jarablus</s>
</seg>
<seg id="556">
<s id="1:556">Explosion during Russian-Turkish joint patrol in Idlib</s>
</seg>
<seg id="557">
<s id="1:557">Attack by occupation forces injures a civilian in Shehba</s>
</seg>
<seg id="558">
<s id="1:558">Occupiers burn down agricultural land in al-Bab</s>
</seg>
<seg id="559">
<s id="1:559">SDF fighter laid to rest in Kobane</s>
</seg>
<seg id="560">
<s id="1:560">Authorities try to prevent participation at Gökçek's funeral</s>
</seg>
<seg id="561">
<s id="1:561">IGFM calls for the release of HDP politician Gülser Yildirim</s>
</seg>
<seg id="562">
<s id="1:562">Banners and slogans against isolation in Istanbul</s>
</seg>
<seg id="563">
<s id="1:563">Signature campaign for Hasankeyf</s>
</seg>
<seg id="564">
<s id="1:564">HPG announces the names of Zînê Wertê martyrs</s>
</seg>
<seg id="565">
<s id="1:565">Intellectuals in Rojhilat call for dialogue over South Kurdistan</s>
</seg>
<seg id="566">
<s id="1:566">5 people jailed in Van for protesting the attack on Zini Werte</s>
</seg>
<seg id="567">
<s id="1:567">KJK warns against new Turkish occupation plans</s>
</seg>
<seg id="568">
<s id="1:568">HPG pays tribute to five martyrs who fell in Zagros</s>
</seg>
<seg id="569">
<s id="1:569">HPG reports guerrilla action in Çele, air raid in South Kurdistan</s>
</seg>
<seg id="570">
<s id="1:570">HPG publishes names of three guerrillas who fell in Heftanin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="571">
<s id="1:571">23 soldiers killed in guerrilla actions from Heftanin to Serhat</s>
</seg>
<seg id="572">
<s id="1:572">YJA Star hit Turkish soldiers in Heftanin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="573">
<s id="1:573">Police raid houses, detain 14 people in Van</s>
</seg>
<seg id="574">
<s id="1:574">Turkish soldiers desecrate guerrilla graves in Bingöl</s>
</seg>
<seg id="575">
<s id="1:575">HPG: Two MIT and three counter-guerrilla members killed in Amed</s>
</seg>
<seg id="576">
<s id="1:576">Two soldiers killed as guerillas hit a covert military unit in Am</s>
</seg>
<seg id="577">
<s id="1:577">HPG commander Zinar Sason martyred in Zap region</s>
</seg>
<seg id="578">
<s id="1:578">One Turkish soldier killed in Heftanin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="579">
<s id="1:579">HPG commemorates guerrilla fighter Eriş Avent Pasin</s>
</seg>
<seg id="580">
<s id="1:580">Remains of HPG guerrilla sent to family by cargo</s>
</seg>
<seg id="581">
<s id="1:581">Protests against feminicide banned in Northern Kurdistan</s>
</seg>
<seg id="582">
<s id="1:582">HDP calls on women to take to the streets on 25 November</s>
</seg>
<seg id="583">
<s id="1:583">Susan Mohammed from Bashur is one of ATHENA40's candidates</s>
</seg>
<seg id="584">
<s id="1:584">Violence against women cases 47 times higher than media reflects</s>
</seg>
<seg id="585">
<s id="1:585">Istanbul police detain 7 people distributing leaflets for 25 Nov.</s>
</seg>
<seg id="586">
<s id="1:586">Dozens of women murdered or committed suicide in South Kurdistan</s>
</seg>
<seg id="587">
<s id="1:587">Mustafa Salimi's death sentence was carried out in Saqez Prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="588">
<s id="1:588">A Kurdish citizen was arrested by Ettelaat</s>
</seg>
<seg id="589">
<s id="1:589">Four Kurdish cultural activists have been sentenced to 36 months in prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="590">
<s id="1:590">Arrest of a former prisoner in Saqez</s>
</seg>
<seg id="591">
<s id="1:591">A Kurdish citizen sentenced to one year in discretionary imprisonment</s>
</seg>
<seg id="592">
<s id="1:592">A Kurdish environmental activist was sentenced to six years in prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="593">
<s id="1:593">A Kurdish citizen was arrested in Sanandaj</s>
</seg>
<seg id="594">
<s id="1:594">IRGC officials threatened the PDKI with further attacks</s>
</seg>
<seg id="595">
<s id="1:595">The director of Ershad Bureau in Paweh threatened Kurdish cultural activists and poets</s>
</seg>
<seg id="596">
<s id="1:596">A Kurdish citizen was taken to an unknown location after his arrest</s>
</seg>
<seg id="597">
<s id="1:597">Armed clash between Revolutionary Guards and an armed group in Marivan</s>
</seg>
<seg id="598">
<s id="1:598">Three Kurdish Kolbars were killed and wounded in Bazargan, Maku</s>
</seg>
<seg id="599">
<s id="1:599">Another prisoner executed in Sanandaj prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="600">
<s id="1:600">Transfer of Kurdish political prisoner from Marivan prison to Sanandaj prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="601">
<s id="1:601">Three Kurdish Kolbars were wounded at Chaldoran border</s>
</seg>
<seg id="602">
<s id="1:602">Saeed Sangar was sentenced to 15 years in prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="603">
<s id="1:603">Shayan Saeedpour was executed</s>
</seg>
<seg id="604">
<s id="1:604">Malakshahi\'s Nowruz Celebration was canceled</s>
</seg>
<seg id="605">
<s id="1:605">One week has passed since the forced disappearance of Hedayat Abdullahpour</s>
</seg>
<seg id="606">
<s id="1:606">Detention of two Kurdish citizens in Sanandaj for unknown reasons</s>
</seg>
<seg id="607">
<s id="1:607">A Kurdish Kolbar was died after being shot by the government troops at the Sardasht's border</s>
</seg>
<seg id="608">
<s id="1:608">Execution of two other prisoners in Sanandaj and Urmia</s>
</seg>
<seg id="609">
<s id="1:609">A young man from Mahabad was sentenced to two years in prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="610">
<s id="1:610">Transfer of five Kurdish citizens to Sepah Detention center in Urmia</s>
</seg>
<seg id="611">
<s id="1:611">Satiari welcomed Nowruz</s>
</seg>
<seg id="612">
<s id="1:612">Execution of a prisoner accused of "murder" in Urmia Central Prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="613">
<s id="1:613">Two Kurdish youths from Oshnovieh were arrested by intelligence forces</s>
</seg>
<seg id="614">
<s id="1:614">Danish citizens were discouraged from traveling to Kurdistan, Balochistan and Khuzestan</s>
</seg>
<seg id="615">
<s id="1:615">Arrest of another Kurdish youth in Marivan for raising Kurdistan flag</s>
</seg>
<seg id="616">
<s id="1:616">Head of Nojin Socio-cultural Association Kamyaran's branch sentenced to three years in prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="617">
<s id="1:617">A Kurdish Kolbar was died after government troops fired at the Baneh's border</s>
</seg>
<seg id="618">
<s id="1:618">Arrest of a Kurdish citizen in Sarpol-e Zahab</s>
</seg>
<seg id="619">
<s id="1:619">An injured young Ahvazi due to mine blast</s>
</seg>
<seg id="620">
<s id="1:620">A Kurdish youth was arrested after being summoned to Urmia's Ettelaat</s>
</seg>
<seg id="621">
<s id="1:621">Two Kurdish Kolbars were wounded at the Sardasht border</s>
</seg>
<seg id="622">
<s id="1:622">Arrest of a citizen for raising the Kurdistan flag</s>
</seg>
<seg id="623">
<s id="1:623">The plainclothes arrested a Kurdish youth in Sanandaj</s>
</seg>
<seg id="624">
<s id="1:624">Karim Parwizi : we are looking forward to seeing the United States’ and other countries’ political support for the Kurdish movement in Rojhelat</s>
</seg>
<seg id="625">
<s id="1:625">Bureau of Properties impounded Kamyaran Singer\'s artistry card</s>
</seg>
<seg id="626">
<s id="1:626">A Kurdish citizen was arrested in Kermanshah</s>
</seg>
<seg id="627">
<s id="1:627">A Kermanshahi citizen was arrested for "cooperating with one of the Kurdish parties"</s>
</seg>
<seg id="628">
<s id="1:628">Komala Refutes the Iranian Ministry of Intelligence’s claim</s>
</seg>
<seg id="629">
<s id="1:629">Two Kurdish Kolbars were killed and wounded after Turkish troops opened fire</s>
</seg>
<seg id="630">
<s id="1:630">Kurdish citizens continue to be detained in Piranshahr</s>
</seg>
<seg id="631">
<s id="1:631">Loghman Ahmadpour was executed in Sanandaj Central Prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="632">
<s id="1:632">The Urmia Military Court has opposed the probation and parole of two Kurdish political prisoners</s>
</seg>
<seg id="633">
<s id="1:633">A Kurdish youth was arrested in Urmia</s>
</seg>
<seg id="634">
<s id="1:634">Arrest of a 18-year-old youth in Oshnavieh</s>
</seg>
<seg id="635">
<s id="1:635">Chia Sohrabi: Adel Bahrami has been deported to Iran after moving to Agri Camp</s>
</seg>
<seg id="636">
<s id="1:636">Saghez Provision Council adopted decisions to deal vigorously with the New Year celebrations</s>
</seg>
<seg id="637">
<s id="1:637">Two Kurdish youths were arrested by intelligence forces in Urmia and Piranshahr</s>
</seg>
<seg id="638">
<s id="1:638">The sentence of a labor activist in the Sanandaj Court of Appeals was upheld</s>
</seg>
<seg id="639">
<s id="1:639">Arrest of a Kurdish teenager in Piranshahr</s>
</seg>
<seg id="640">
<s id="1:640">Parisa Seifi sentenced to three years in discretionary prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="641">
<s id="1:641">The bomb explosion killed a 37-year-old citizen in Sarpol Zahab</s>
</seg>
<seg id="642">
<s id="1:642">Three Kolbars killed and wounded by government gunfire</s>
</seg>
<seg id="643">
<s id="1:643">Three members of the Revolutionary Guards were killed in a military clash</s>
</seg>
<seg id="644">
<s id="1:644">The fire set on Vajin, a Cultural-Artistic Center in Mariwan was intentional</s>
</seg>
<seg id="645">
<s id="1:645">Arrest of two Kurdish citizens in Piranshahr for unknown reasons</s>
</seg>
<seg id="646">
<s id="1:646">37 civilians were killed and wounded in a landmine explosion in Iran and Kurdistan during 1398</s>
</seg>
<seg id="647">
<s id="1:647">Transfer of a citizen from Piranshahr to Urmia prison for serving his sentence</s>
</seg>
<seg id="648">
<s id="1:648">The death sentence of a prisoner accused of "murder" was carried out in Sanandaj prison</s>
</seg>
<seg id="649">
<s id="1:649">Osman Mustafa Pour, most prominent Kurdish political prisoner still deprived of leaving</s>
</seg>
<seg id="650">
<s id="1:650">Iran unveils smart laser-guided projectile</s>
</seg>
</p>
